Rafael Moises Abuawad Vivanco

Blockchain Developer

Github - Articles - Twitter (X) - Linked In

Cochabamba, Bolivia rafael.abuawad@live.com

ABOUT ME

I am a highly skilled software developer specializing in the exciting realm of Blockchain and Decentralized Applications. With over 6 years of professional experience, I have successfully crafted and delivered 30+ projects for diverse clients, ranging from individuals to small and large teams. My expertise lies in harnessing the power of cutting-edge technology.

EXPERIENCE

Encora, Cochabamba — *Blockchain Developer*

SEPTEMBER 2023 - PRESENT

- Created a full stack web3 application that enabled our client's customers to mint NFTs without the need to pay for gas fees.
- Developed an indexed graph API that allowed an ecommerce platform to fetch NFT metadata, as well as balances, transfers, and more
- Created and presented an introduction to Vyper to a new audience of developers.
- Created and presented multiple talks about distributed systems, crypto economics, and more.

Metacrafters, New York, USA — Web3 Course Creator

APRIL 2023

- Created a complete course from scratch on Solidity, detailing how
 to create decentralized applications, focusing on DeFi and NFTs,
 and how to develop smart contracts on the Avalanche network,
 with more than 800 students.
- Created a complete course on how to use **Go** to create a blockchain from scratch, and having it up and running.

Encora, Cochabamba— Web Content Specialist

APRIL 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2023

- Employed technologies such as Velocity, Liquid, and Jinja to create templates and web designs utilized by the marketing team within an American Tech Company.
- Used **CSS** and **SASS** to implement new designs and ensure visual consistency across various web platforms.
- Harnessed the power and flexibility of **Vue.js** to craft an interactive and user-friendly interface for the internal No-Code tools' UI.

MAIN SKILLS

Leadership, Effective Communication, Problem Solving, Algorithmic Thinking, Attention To Detail, Innovation, Decision Making, Creativity, Mathematics

TECHNOLOGIES

Vyper, Solidity, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NextJS, Vite, GraphQL, Redux, Bun, Git, HTML, CSS, Python, Django, Flask, FastAPI, Apeworx, Brownie, Foundry, Echidna, Hardhat, Truffle, Go

LANGUAGES

Spanish, English (C2)

CERTIFICATES

Blockchain Expert
Azure AI-900
Updraft's Advanced Foundry

EDUCATION

Computer Science UMSS

Contractor, Global — Full Stack Software Development

NOVEMBER 2017 - MARCH 2022

Developed multiple applications and systems using Angular, React, Python, Node.js, GraphQL, Vue.js,.NET Core, and Firebase. Key projects include:

- Created a Full-stack inventory and sales management system for Pizza Club (Angular 12, Node.js, GraphQL)
- Developed Internal tooling for account and finance management for Pizza Club (Angular 12, Node.js, GraphQL)
- Developed a desktop application for efficient communication and collaboration for Tecnologica S.A (Vue.js 2,.NET Core)
- Created Full-stack application for managing inventory and personnel for Latigid S.R.L (Firebase, Node.js, Vue.js 2)
- Implemented Landing site and internal tooling for CoderBlend (Astro, Vue. js 3, Firebase)
- Created a Web Scraping bot that searched for data on my client's partners websites using Python.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Encora, Cochabamba — Team lead & project architect

2024

- Created all the technical requirements for a Liquid Static Analyzer Tool, that was used heavily in our project.
- Completed tasks on time and delegated work to teammates to get the first version of the software out as soon as possible.
- Worked on a tight schedule, but we were able to deliver the project on-time, without any issues.